=Spring Fever= =Episode 27=
=حمى الربيع= =الحلقة 27=
Lord Xia.
اللورد شيا.
How could it be you?
كيف يمكن أن تكون أنت؟
Over a dozen of my family members were wrongfully executed.
لقد تم إعدام أكثر من اثني عشر فردًا من عائلتي ظلماً.
Even now,
حتى الآن،
you still try to pin false charges
لا تزال تحاول توجيه اتهامات كاذبة
on my family.
على عائلتي.
Why couldn't I be here?
لماذا لا أستطيع أن أكون هنا؟
Are you satisfied now?
هل أنت راضي الآن؟
Not enough.
ليس كافيا.
What more do you want from me?
ماذا تريد مني أكثر من ذلك؟
I want you to die with full clarity.
أريدك أن تموت بكل وضوح.
Dong Kui.
دونغ كوي.
Scholar Dong.
الباحث دونغ.
What you truly wanted to protect
ما أردت حمايته حقًا
are your family members back in Yingzhou,
هل أفراد عائلتك عادوا إلى ينغتشو؟
right?
يمين؟
You fear they'd end up as slaves like me.
أنت تخشى أن ينتهي بهم الأمر كعبيد مثلي.
Your essays were no worse than Xia Ciyi's.
لم تكن مقالاتك أسوأ من مقالات شيا سيي.
You merely lacked fortune.
لقد كنت تفتقر إلى الحظ فقط.
But jealousy drove you to kill your sworn brother.
لكن الغيرة دفعتك إلى قتل أخيك المحلف.
N-No. I don't know what you are talking about.
ن-لا، لا أعرف عما تتحدث.
Dong Kui died long ago.
لقد مات دونغ كوي منذ زمن طويل.
I-I am Xia Ciyi.
أنا شيا Ciyi.
I have two versions of that past incident.
لدي نسختين من تلك الحادثة الماضية.
Do you want to hear them?
هل تريد أن تسمعهم؟
Lord Gao.
اللورد جاو.
You...
أنت...
Y-You are that attendant back then?
ن-أنت ذلك الموظف في ذلك الوقت؟
Your memory serves well.
ذاكرتك تخدم بشكل جيد.
Had I not known your identity,
لو لم أعرف هويتك،
I might not have recognized you.
ربما لم أتعرف عليك.
Every detail and every person
كل التفاصيل وكل شخص
from that night
من تلك الليلة
are all burned into my memory.
لقد تم حرقها كلها في ذاكرتي.
I'll never forget them as long as I live.
لن أنساهم أبدًا طالما أنا على قيد الحياة.
What you and I witnessed that night
ما شهدناه أنا وأنت تلك الليلة
were indeed different.
كانت مختلفة بالفعل.
Stop talking! You...
توقف عن الكلام! أنت...
Y-You dare hit me?
ن-هل تجرؤ على ضربي؟
(So from the very beginning, I was being used.)
(لذا، منذ البداية، كنت أستخدم.)
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
You thought it was jealousy,
ظننت أنها الغيرة
but you didn't know there was a poison
ولكنك لم تعلم أن هناك سمًا
that when mixed in wine,
أنه عندما يخلط بالنبيذ،
could make even saints
يمكن أن يصنع حتى القديسين
fly into rage.
الطيران في الغضب.
Otherwise, how could someone
وإلا فكيف يمكن لأحد أن
wait outside the window in advance?
الانتظار خارج النافذة مسبقًا؟
Dong Kui.
دونغ كوي.
I'm giving you the chance to overthrow Madam Lu.
أنا أعطيك الفرصة للإطاحة بالسيدة لو.
Choose wisely.
إختر بحكمة.
But why should I do this?
ولكن لماذا يجب علي أن أفعل هذا؟
You won't spare me either, will you?
أنت لن تدخرني أيضًا، أليس كذلك؟
Yes. Compared to established families like the Lus,
نعم. بالمقارنة مع العائلات العريقة مثل عائلة لوس،
you're easier to handle.
أنت أسهل في التعامل.
The public outrage you stirred remains unresolved.
إن الغضب العام الذي أثرته لا يزال دون حل.
If you die,
إذا مت،
Madam Lu will create greater chaos.
السيدة لو ستخلق فوضى أكبر.
Countless will perish in Ningzhou.
سوف يموت عدد لا يحصى في نينغتشو.
I see.
أرى.
You want me
انت تريدني
to eliminate Madam Lu first.
للقضاء على السيدة لو أولاً.
Because I hold more authority here than Shen Que,
لأنني أملك سلطة أكبر هنا من شين كيو،
and know more Lu family secrets.
وتعرف على المزيد من أسرار عائلة لو.
Yes.
نعم.
But if you take blame for Madam Lu today,
ولكن إذا كنت تتحمل اللوم على السيدة لو اليوم،
and she falls to Shen Que later,
وتسقط أمام شين كيو لاحقًا،
your crimes will still be exposed.
جرائمك سوف تظل مكشوفة
You'll drag your family into this as well.
سوف تجر عائلتك إلى هذا أيضًا.
But if you handle Madam Lu first,
ولكن إذا تعاملت مع السيدة لو أولاً،
you'll not only avenge yourself,
لن تنتقم لنفسك فقط،
but also secure your family's survival.
بل وتأمين بقاء عائلتك أيضًا.
Two options ahead.
هناك خيارين في الأمام.
Choose wisely.
إختر بحكمة.
Were you scared just now?
هل كنت خائفة للتو؟
Of what?
من ماذا؟
I'm one step closer
أنا أقرب بخطوة واحدة
to avenging my father,
للانتقام لأبي،
my mother, and Mu.
والدتي ومو.
There's only excitement. No fear.
لا يوجد سوى الإثارة. لا خوف.
But now,
ولكن الآن،
I feel some concern.
أشعر ببعض القلق.
Concern about what?
القلق بشأن ماذا؟
As the book says, don't corner the desperate.
كما يقول الكتاب، لا تحاصر اليائسين.
We've driven Prefect Xia to desperation,
لقد دفعنا المحافظ شيا إلى اليأس،
and set this desperate man against a tiger.
ووضع هذا الرجل اليائس في مواجهة النمر.
Men like him
الرجال يحبونه
will do anything
سوف افعل اي شيء
for survival.
من أجل البقاء.
As long as he stops preying on people,
طالما أنه يتوقف عن افتراس الناس،
I'll counter any scheme.
سأواجه أي مخطط.
Let's hope his choice doesn't disappoint us.
نأمل أن اختياره لا يخيب آمالنا.
It's strange. This bougainvillea
إنه أمر غريب. هذه الجهنمية
only bloomed sparsely this year.
ازدهرت بشكل متفرق هذا العام.
Have it chopped down.
قم بتقطيعه.
Yes.
نعم.
Transplant a better one next year.
زرع واحدة أفضل في العام القادم.
Understood.
مفهومة.
There's been no movement from the Prefect's Mansion yet?
لم يكن هناك أي تحرك من قصر المحافظ حتى الآن؟
No, there hasn't been any movement yet.
لا، لم يكن هناك أي تحرك حتى الآن.
You may leave now.
يمكنك المغادرة الآن.
Understood.
مفهومة.
Ciyi,
عواء،
you still don't understand?
هل مازلت لا تفهم؟
It seems
يبدو أنه
you no longer remember the kindness I showed you in the past.
لم تعد تتذكر اللطف الذي أظهرته لك في الماضي.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Last night, I heard of a poisonous herb called Leigong.
سمعت ليلة أمس عن عشبة سامة تسمى ليجونج.
Brewed in wine, it could drive even saints to madness.
إذا تم تخميره في النبيذ، فإنه يمكن أن يقود حتى القديسين إلى الجنون.
I could have had my own life.
كان بإمكاني أن أحظى بحياتي الخاصة.
I could have been a good man. It was all your fault.
كان بإمكاني أن أكون رجلاً صالحًا، لكن كل هذا كان خطؤك.
You schemed against me step by step.
لقد خططت ضدي خطوة بخطوة.
My hands are stained with blood.
يدي ملطخة بالدماء.
There's no turning back now.
لا يوجد عودة إلى الوراء الآن.
All of this is thanks to you.
كل هذا بفضلك .
Today,
اليوم،
I'll properly repay your kindness.
سأرد لك لطفك كما ينبغي.
Dong Kui, regarding what happened back then,
دونغ كوي، فيما يتعلق بما حدث في ذلك الوقت،
neither of us is innocent.
لا أحد منا بريء.
That pirate who killed people with throwing daggers
ذلك القرصان الذي قتل الناس بالخناجر
outside the window
خارج النافذة
has already been imprisoned.
لقد تم سجنه بالفعل.
As for me,
أما بالنسبة لي،
I am just a pitiful fool
أنا مجرد أحمق مثير للشفقة
you coerced and deceived.
لقد أكرهت وخدعت.
My crimes aren't grave enough to exterminate my entire clan.
جرائمي ليست خطيرة بما يكفي للقضاء على عشيرتي بأكملها.
But you...
ولكنك...
You're different.
أنت مختلف.
You want mutual destruction?
هل تريد الدمار المتبادل؟
I only want you destructed,
أنا فقط أريد تدميرك،
not me.
ليس انا.
In your dreams!
في أحلامك!
Seize him!
إمسكوه!
You...
أنت...
Madam, don't blame him.
سيدتي، لا تلوميه.
Dogs naturally follow
تتبع الكلاب بشكل طبيعي
whoever feeds them,
من يطعمهم
right?
يمين؟
Good.
جيد.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Xia Ciyi,
شيا سيي,
well played.
لعبت بشكل جيد.
You flatter me.
أنت تملقني.
You taught me well, Madam.
لقد علمتني جيدًا سيدتي.
(Confession Letter) I wrote this confession last night.
(رسالة اعتراف) كتبت هذا الاعتراف الليلة الماضية.
And you
وأنت
just need to copy it
فقط بحاجة إلى نسخها
word for word
كلمة بكلمة
and replace the name with yours.
واستبدال الاسم باسمك.
Only in this way
بهذه الطريقة فقط
will the Lu family remain standing.
هل ستبقى عائلة لو واقفة؟
Your grandson will remain head of the Lu family.
حفيدك سيبقى رئيسًا لعائلة لو.
Madam, please be careful.
سيدتي، من فضلك كن حذرا.
Shi'an.
شيعان.
I know you're awake.
أعلم أنك مستيقظ.
You're just holding resentment,
أنت فقط تحمل الاستياء،
ignoring me, aren't you?
تتجاهلني، أليس كذلك؟
Fine.
بخير.
Then you just listen.
ثم عليك فقط الاستماع.
Xia Ciyi can't defeat Shen Que.
Xia Ciyi لا يستطيع هزيمة Shen Que.
If he troubles the Lu family after my death,
إذا أزعج عائلة لو بعد وفاتي،
don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
Concubine Ye has a conscience.
المحظية يي لديها ضمير.
Last time, you saved Jin.
في المرة الماضية، قمت بإنقاذ جين.
This time, you took poison for her.
هذه المرة، أخذت السم من أجلها.
As long as she and Shen Que are here,
طالما أنها وشين كيو هنا،
they'll protect you.
سوف يحمونك.
Drink this.
اشرب هذا.
Drink it all.
اشربها كلها
You
أنت
will fully recover.
سوف يتعافى بشكل كامل.
Madam Lu made this herself last night.
السيدة لو صنعت هذا بنفسها الليلة الماضية.
Master Shi'an, please drink it.
سيد شيآن، من فضلك اشربه.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
you can do
يمكنك فعل ذلك
whatever you want.
أياً كان ما تريد.
I'll be gone.
سوف أذهب.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
you must obtain
يجب عليك الحصول عليها
what you desire yourself.
ما ترغب به لنفسك.
Madam!
سيدتي!
Grandmother.
جدة.
Grandmother!
جدة!
♪Grind flesh between grit and stone♪
???طحن اللحم بين الحصى والحجر؟؟؟
♪Sink into pain, only then are pearls born♪
???الغرق في الألم، حينها فقط تولد اللآلئ؟؟؟
♪Wait until abyssal darkness stains every inch of skin♪
???انتظر حتى يلطخ الظلام السحيق كل بوصة من الجلد ???
♪Then comes the time to chase the dawn♪
???ثم يأتي الوقت لمطاردة الفجر؟؟؟
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
???سوف أقوم بالمسح عبر الرمال المليئة بالغبار؟؟؟
♪Passing wind♪
???ريح عابرة؟؟؟
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
???تشابك شعري في الرقص؟؟؟
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
???سوف أستند إلى حضنه؟؟؟
♪Wade through deep seas♪
???خوض البحار العميقة؟؟؟
♪Bathing in affection♪
???الاستحمام في المودة؟؟؟
♪Condensing into rain♪
???تتكاثف إلى مطر؟؟؟
♪Who cast a frantic, lingering glance♪
???من الذي ألقى نظرة محمومة ومتأخرة؟
♪Carrying endless tenderness♪
???تحمل حنانًا لا نهاية له؟؟؟
♪Gazing through eons of moonlit winds♪
???التحديق عبر عصور من الرياح المضاءة بالقمر؟؟؟
♪Turn tears to pearls and cradle them within♪
???تحويل الدموع إلى لؤلؤ وضمها إلى داخلها؟؟؟
♪Henceforth we walk the mortal realm♪
???من الآن فصاعدا نسير في عالم البشر؟؟؟
♪Across vast mountains and rivers♪
???عبر الجبال والأنهار الشاسعة؟؟؟
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
???سوف أقوم بالمسح عبر الرمال المليئة بالغبار؟؟؟
♪Passing wind♪
???ريح عابرة؟؟؟
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
???تشابك شعري في الرقص؟؟؟
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
???سوف أستند إلى حضنه؟؟؟